skimresources.com 2011-01-30

# Skimlinks :: Privacy Policy

Welcome to Skimlinks, the simplified affiliate marketing service website operated by Skimbit Ltd ( _“Skimbit”_ ).

Skimbit recognises that your privacy is very important to you and that it is your right to control your personal information. We know that providing personal information is an act of trust and we take that trust seriously. Skimbit will never sell, rent or otherwise disclose any of your personal information, including your email address, to any third party without your prior and explicit consent. Unless you give us specific consent to act otherwise, the following privacy policy will govern how Skimbit handles the personal information that you provide to us.

This is a legal document that sets out how Skimbit handles data that identifies you. You should read it in conjunction with the Skimbit Ltd Terms and Conditions of which this Privacy Policy forms part.

Access to this notice is provided at the bottom of every page on our website and at every point where personally identifiable information may be required.

**Collection And Use Of Information**

What we collect when you apply to use Skimlinks:  
Full name  
Email address  
Telephone number  
Website information  
Bank account details  
Address

How we use it:  
To assess your site’s suitability for Skimlinks  
To contact you to find out more about your site to determine suitability for Skimlinks  
To pay you the commissions you earn through Skimlinks  
To communicate with you on Skimlinks-related matters  
To provide you with order and billing history information

**Use of your information**

We use the non-personally identifiable information and certain technical information about your computer in order to operate, maintain and manage Skimlinks.

**Skimlinks technology**

Once you are accepted to use Skimlinks, and have added the Skimlinks code to your site template, it will download a javascript file to your user’s computer when they view one of your webpages. This javascript file will transfer to Skimbit each outbound URL that a user clicks for processing. Skimlinks technology assesses these URLs, and where appropriate, turns the link into an affiliate link. Skimbit stores the URLs that are clicked, and information about the sale or acquisition through the respective affiliate network. However, no user’s personally identifiable information is stored by Skimbit, and all data stored is anonymised or aggregated.

We recommend that you add to your own Privacy Policy to indicate to your users that you are engaged in affiliate marketing through a third-party service, but that no personally identifiable information is obtained or stored at any time.

**Cookies**

Skimbit uses cookies to help speed up the login process and for security purposes. A cookie is a small amount of data that identifies you as a unique user that is sent to your web browser from a web server and stored on your computer.

We use cookies to improve the quality of our service and make the service easier to use for our members. We do this by storing user preferences in cookies and by tracking user trends - for example, we use cookies to allow you to automatically log in to the service after the first user session.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Be aware, however, that some parts of Skimlinks may not function properly if you refuse cookies.

More detailed information on cookies may be found in the Help section of your web browser.

**Our commitment to the privacy of children**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is extremely important to us. No part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13. We never seek to collect or maintain information at our website from those under the age of 13, but if it comes to our attention that we have received information about a child under the age of 13 that information will be immediately deleted from our records.

**Information Sharing And Disclosure**

Skimbit is committed to protecting your personal information. We will not disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent except:

**Disclosure for legal reasons**

We reserve the right to communicate such of a User’s personal information as we hold to third parties which seek the disclosure of it, and which make a legally compliant request for its disclosure.

**Performance of our operations**

The service is necessary for the performance of our operations: mail delivery, hosting services, protecting us from fraud, and payment of your account.

**Changes in Skimbit’s business**

If the assets Skimbit use to operate its business are acquired by a third party, we may transfer personal data we then hold to that party. If Skimbit buys or sells subsidiaries or business units then in such transactions customer information is one of the transferred assets, but would remain subject to the commitments made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy or equivalent.

**Aggregate business analyses**

Skimbit also provides analyses of our customers in the aggregate to prospective partners, advertisers and other third parties. We do this so that we, along with our business partners, can understand you better, and so we can keep bringing you first-rate services. We may also disclose, on an anonymous basis, literal statements made by our customers. At no time, however, will we disclose personal information about specific customers.

Linked websites are not under the control of Skimbit and we are not responsible for the conduct of companies linked to our website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website we advise you to examine their terms and conditions of use.

**Transfer of information**

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United Kingdom or any other country in which Skimbit maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside your country.

We will not supply your personal data to a third party for commercial exploitation unless explicitly authorised by you; so you can rest assured that we will not sell your name, personal details or email addresses to any third party without express consent from you.

The only circumstances in which we will provide any of your personal data to a third party for non-commercial purposes are those contained in this Privacy Policy.

**Security And Prevention Against Loss, Misuse Or Alteration Of Information**

All information you provide to us is stored in the UK and USA on secure servers that are protected in secure facilities including firewall protection.

Skimbit has implemented such technology and security features, as well as strict internal guidelines, to safeguard the privacy of your personal information from unauthorised access or improper use. We will continue to enhance security as new technology becomes available.

While we make every effort to ensure that your information is secure on our system, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.

Your Skimlinks account information is password-protected for your privacy and security. You can play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of your password used on the Skimlinks web site. We recommend that you change your password from time to time for additional security. Please advise us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

Access authorisation is granted to key Skimbit staff only. Backups are run to prevent loss of information, and our Internet servers are housed in secure facilities.

We have security measures in place to protect our customer database and access to this database is restricted internally. However, it remains each Member’s responsibility:

to protect against unauthorised access to your details;  
to ensure against use by anyone else of the Skimlinks Service through the machine that the member uses while they are logged on to the Skimlinks Service;  
to log off or exit from the Skimlinks Service when not using it;  
and to keep his/her password secret

**Opt-Out Policy: Your Ability To Edit And Cancel Your Account**

You can access your account on the site to update and correct the details that we gathered when you subscribed. You must be logged in to access this information. All information is password-protected so no one can access the information but you

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

From time to time, Skimbit will review and may edit this policy in accordance with potential changes to our business and as required by law. Skimbit reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time.

**Contacting Skimbit**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with Skimbit, you can contact us here. You can also use this address if you wish to request from Skimbit a copy of the personal data we hold about you.

As a subscriber you have certain rights under the Data Protection Act 1998. You have the right to be told what personal information we hold about you on our database. Should you wish to exercise that right, or if you have any questions concerning the Skimbit privacy policy please contact us via the following channels:

Skimbit Ltd  
3rd Floor, Transworld House  
100 City Road, London EC1Y 2BP

(Please note that by English law we are entitled to charge you a small sum for providing this information)

**Data Protection Information**

You can obtain further information about data protection laws by visiting the Information Commissioner’s web site at [www.dataprotection.gov.uk](http://www.dataprotection.gov.uk/)
